

Aman Kimothi

Senior Software Engineer at Amadeus Labs, Bangalore

An engineer with 2+ years of experience working in teams handling mission critical applications. I've got experience of building production ready solutions from the proof of concept stages saving millions of dollars for organization. My main aim is to apply my skills and knowledge to add value to the organization.

www.codechef.com/users/amankimothi100

9557799020

in linkedin.com/in/aman-kimothi

EDUCATION

B. Tech - Information Technology SRMIST , Chennai , CGPA - 9.61

Class 12th - ISC St. Joseph's Academy, Dehradun - 95%

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer - AmadeusProjects - AuditTrail, RMG and JFS

07/2018 - Present Bengaluru

Tasks

- FND team handling formatting, storage and delivery of the SMS, Emails and documents, like itineraries, boarding passes, bag tags, reports, etc, to the client through various channels.
- Worked in a mission critical middleware application which deals with the storage and formatting of the documents.
- Owner of multiple internal projects/tools majorly in Java.

Software Engineer Intern - AmadeusEnterprise Service Bus Registry Automation

01/2018 - 05/2018 Bengaluru Tasks

- Service Integrator acts as a ESB which handles all the transfer of data and requests coming from outside/within Amadeus.
- Automation of a manual service registry change in the SI like new service publication, using Django Web Framework.

Back End Developer Intern - Morgentec Security Management System

12/2016 - 01/2017 New Delhi

Tasks

- Developed RESTful APIs of a security management system for a company providing security guard services.
- Java, SQL and Jersey Framework were used for development.

EXTRA & CO-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

Team SRMSAT - Satellite Club 11/2015 - 12/2017

Team Robocon - Robotics Club 04/2015 - 10/2015

Technical Head of Team Gen-Y - Multidisciplinary Club

SKILLS

Java Python Spring Framework Scripting(Basic)

PROJECTS

Web HTML to Email HTML Convertor

- Conversion to email compatible HTML which can be delivered it to different Email clients like Outlook and Gmail using Java.
- Conversion of HTML 5 to older version using Graph algorithms as the latest tags and styles are not consistently supported in email clients.

NAS TO AMAZON S3 STORAGE MIGRATION

 Migration of storage of big documents from Network Attached Stored (NAS) to Amazon S3 Object Storage in Amadeus using Java.

AUDIT TRAIL FRAMEWORK

 Storage of all events related to creation, updates and deletion of different resources used in formatting like images using Java.

HEALTH MONITORING SYSTEM

 A wearable health monitoring device used to observe the pulse rate, humidity and body temperature using Arduino C and Java.

CERTIFICATES

CodeChef Certified Data Structures and Algorithms Programme (CCDSAP - Score of 750/750)

Machine Learning by Andrew Ng, Coursera

Deep Learning Specialization Courses on Coursera

ACHIEVEMENTS

27th rank in Code Gladiators, 2019

Code Gladiators event was organized by TechGig which saw a total participation of over 2,50,000+ people worldwide.

1st rank in CodingGame

Ranked 1st in India and 12th globally in a bot programming competition on CodinGame platform organized within Amadeus.

Runner up in 'Code Mortem'

National Level Tech. Fest, SRM Institute of Science and Technology.

High Flyer Award in O2 and O4 of 2019

Awarded by Director in Amadeus for the work in HTML Plugin.

CODECHEF RANKINGS

Country Rank: 6099 Global Rank: 8616

Nov'17 Lunchtime: 161 Nov'17 Cook-Off: 297